胎儿已然显现出男性特征
The child had the appearance of a male,
约有四个月大小
about four months old.
然而…
However…
胎儿
The foetus…
有畸形的迹象
there were signs of deformity, of abnormality.
或许
Perhaps, after all,
王后的流产未尝不是好事
the Queen's miscarriage was a blessing in disguise.
陛下
Majesty.
- 夫人 - 大使先生
- Madame. - Monsieur Ambassadeur…
我请求你 务必说服弗兰西斯国王
I beg you: King Francis must be persuaded.
恩准我女儿伊丽莎白与贵国王子的婚事
to accept the marriage of his son to our daughter Elizabeth,
使我不至于被废黜或失宠
so that I may not be ruined or lost,
我很清楚自己即将陷入
for I see myself very near that and in more trouble and grief than.
前所未有的悲惨与不幸之中
I was ever in before my marriage…
我现在无法对你和盘托出
I cannot speak to you more fully now,
亦不敢将忧惧付诸书简 但请求您
nor dare I express my fears in writing. But please,
念在我为法国所做的一切
after everything I've done for France,
如果拥戴我 就请务必倾尽全力
as you love me, do the best you can for me,
拜托了
for God's sake.
爱德华·西摩阁下到
Mr. Edward Seymour.
- 西摩少爷 - 大臣阁下
- Master Seymour. - Mr. Secretary.
我们对彼此不甚了解
We don't know each other well.
但我们会相熟起来 我深信不疑
But we shall. I have every confidence.
陛下欲任命你
It is His Majesty's pleasure.
为枢密侍郎
to appoint you a Gentleman of the Privy Chamber.
如此一来便可每日伴驾于陛下左右
In that capacity, you will attend His Majesty daily,
听候陛下差遣 你日后会明白
and as he sees fit to use you. It is, you will understand that,
这是个很特殊 拥有特权的职位
a special and privileged position.
我明白
I do understand.
大臣阁下 我不胜荣幸
And I am deeply honored, Mr. Secretary.
还有一事
There is… one more thing.
陛下向我暗示
His Majesty has indicated to me.
他有意追求令妹
he would like to pay court to your sister, from time to time,
但为避免有关二人的流言蜚语
although to avoid any scandal attaching himself to your sister's name.
他们只会在有家人在场的情况下相见
only in the presence of a member, or members, of your family.
因此 我非常乐于
In which case, I am more than happy to.
向你及你的家人提供便利
offer you and your family.
让出我在宫中的私人房间
my private chambers in the palace.
此房间恰好与国王私人房间相邻
As it happens, they are adjacent to the King's private chambers,
之间以走廊衔接 以保私密
the connecting gallery for greater privacy.
大臣阁下甚是慷慨
You are most generous, Mr. Secretary.
相信家父定会报答您的好意
I am sure my father will like to repay your kindness.
你把你的房间让给西摩家了？
You've given the Seymours your rooms?
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
蠢材
Idiot.
我已御准革除
We have just given royal assent to the Act stripping.
林恩镇诺里奇的主教职位
the bishopric of Norwich of the town of Lynn.
任命托马斯·波林 威尔特郡伯爵为新的继任者
The new beneficiary is to be Thomas Boleyn, Earl of Wiltshire.
我有意赐他两所解散的修道院
I also intend giving him two of the dissolved abbeys.
务必向他转达这个好消息
You must inform him of his good fortune.
遵命 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
要确保无人知晓我们的计划 克伦威尔
No one must know our plans, Mr. Cromwell.
过来 珍 让我看看你
Come here, Jane. Let me look at you.
你真是美极了
How beautiful you are!
- 准备好了吗 - 是的
- Ready? - Yes.
我们走吧
Shall we?
- 珍 - 陛下
- Jane. - Your Majesty.
我有件东西要给你
I have something for you.
打开它
Now open it.
谢陛下
Thank you.
我将永生珍藏
I will treasure this all my life.
藏于我心
And if they ever open my grave, they will find it again,
至死不渝
right next to my heart.
陛下
Majesty.
我不明白他为什么到现在还不向玛琪求婚
I wonder why, after all this time, he still will not marry Madge?
我认为诺里斯与其说是为玛琪
I think Norris comes.
不如说是为陛下而来
into your chamber more for Your Majesty than he does for Madge.
- 为我？- 正是
- For me? - Yeah.
- 克伦威尔的房间？- 是的
- Cromwell's rooms? - Yes.
这是什么？
What is that?
一个盒式挂件 陛下
It's a locket, Your Majesty.
让我看看
Let me see it.
让我看清楚
大臣阁下
Mr. Secretary!
陛下
Your Majesty.
我有好消息向您禀报
I have some good news for Your Majesty.
国会已经通过
The Bill for the dissolution.
解散大型修道院的法案
of the large monasteries has just been passed Parliament.
我们的改革进展迅速
Our reformation is moving apace.
大臣阁下 听闻约克郡的索里修道院
I have been told privately, Mr. Secretary, that the King has already sold.
已由某朝臣买下
Sawley Abbey in Yorkshire to one of his courtiers,
尽管这项法案还没有列入法令全书
even though the Bill has not yet reached the statute book, and.
仅仅是基于你的建议
plainly on your advice.
我们改革的初衷并非为个人敛财
Our reformation was never meant to be about personal gain.
修道院不应出售
Religious houses should not be sold off.
而应加以善用
but converted to better uses.
夫人
Madam,
没收的财产仍将用于供奉上帝
the confiscated assets will be used to the pleasure of Almighty God.
造福国家
and to the profit of this realm.
虽然现在我们微不足道
which is but a pygmy,
但他日定当富敌西班牙
but will one day be greater even than Spain!
这么说 你把私人房间让给西摩家是真的了？
So is it true you have given your private rooms here to the Seymours?
我是堂堂英格兰王后 回答我 是否属实？
I am the Queen of England. You will answer me. Is it true?
是 确有其事
Yes. It's true.
你太目中无人了 克伦威尔阁下
You have over-reached yourself, Mr. Cromwell.
相信我 你已危在旦夕
Believe me, you have placed yourself in very great danger.
你相信我说的吗
Do you believe me?
还是你认为我已经无力毁掉你
Or do you assume I no longer posses the power to crush you?
那么你就大错特错了 克伦威尔阁下
It would be an easy mistake to make, Mr. Cromwell.
我想应当物归原主
I thought you might like this returned to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安 阁下
Good evening Your Excellency,
请进 请让我为您收好帽子
Please, may I take your hat?
帝国大使阁下来访
His Excellency the Imperial Ambassador.
尤斯塔斯 您不辞辛劳前往沟岸区真是太好了
Ah, Eustace. It's so good of you to come all the way to Shoreditch.
相信我 大臣阁下
Believe me, Mr. Secretary,
能有幸与您相谈 走再远的路我都愿意
I would travel a great deal further for the pleasure of talking to you.
恕我直言
May I be blunt?
你与王后吵翻 可有此事
Is it true that you have fallen out with Queen Anne?
确有此事
Yes.
她对我恨之入骨
I believe she hates me.
想置我于死地
wants to have me executed.
你不惧怕吗
Are you not afraid?
不
No.
我充分信任我的主上
No I trust my master so much…
我认为她不能把我怎么样
I fancy she can't do me any harm.
无论如何 我惟愿你
Nevertheless, I cannot but wish you.
有个宽厚仁慈的女主人
a more gracious mistress.
一个更加感激你为陛下
One more grateful for the.
鞠躬尽瘁的女主人
inestimable service you have done the King.
只是随便说说
For the sake of argument,
假设国王正在考虑另立新后
suppose the King was considering taking another wife?
这对他非常有利
It would certainly be to his advantage.
国王陛下
For here is a King.
对无法生下男性子嗣大失所望
who has so far been disappointed of male issue,
他也深知目前这段婚姻
and who knows very well that his present marriage.
永远不会得到法律认可
will never be held as lawful.
国王陛下请你进宫见驾
The king requests your presence at the court.
我确信他想与皇帝陛下缔结新的联盟
I am sure he wishes to confirm a new alliance with the Emperor.
至于其他的意思 我不敢妄断
What else he means to tell you, I cannot guess.
那么我热切期待
Then I look forward.
谒见陛下 大臣阁下
eagerly to finding out, Mr. Secretary.
夫人
Madam,
洛克福特夫人求见
Lady Rochford.
洛克福特夫人
Lady Rochford,
有什么我能做的吗
what can I do for you?
请让您的弟弟对我体贴一些
You could ask your brother to be kind to me.
他冷酷至极
He is cruel in every way.
得了 我不信
Come now… I don't believe you.
他另结新欢
There are others he has preferred to me.
小声点
Hush!
你不明白
You don't understand.
他没有把我当作妻子
He does not treat me as his proper wife,
如国王待你这般
as the King treats you.
我来告诉你吧 洛克福特夫人
Let me tell you something, Lady Rochford.
国王根本不能满足一个女人
The King cannot satisfy a woman.
他既无能 也无力
He has neither the skill, nor the virility.
我们必须放弃与法国结盟的念头
We must give up the idea of a French alliance.
国王似乎执意反对
The King seems implacably against it, just as he seems.
他越来越倾向于与神圣罗马帝国结盟
more and more inclined to embrace a new alliance with the Emperor…
你在听我说吗
Are you listening to me?
是的 父亲
Yes, father.
看来众臣都更支持与帝国结盟
It seems that most of the country is still in favor.
倘若我们逆流而行
of an Imperial alliance, so it would serve us.
将无任何益处
nothing to swim against the tide.
不
No.
帝国大使已经应邀入宫
The Imperial Ambassador is to be received at court.
你应殷勤款待之
You will make a great fuss of him. In the first place.
首先 请他吻你的脸颊
by inviting him to kiss your cheek.
之后 你和国王将与他共进晚餐
Then you and the King will dine with him,
你要在其他使臣面前
and you will say some harsh things against the French.
竭力批判法国
in the presence of the other ambassadors say how they.
背信弃义 两面三刀之类
have betrayed your trust, are hypocrites and false friends.
- 所有你能想到的类似言辞 - 是 父亲
- Whatever you can think of. - Yes Father.
安妮 我们已经走到这步
Anne, we have come so far.
不容任何人毁灭我们的基业
No one is going to be allowed to destroy us.
没有人
No one!
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
我明白
I understand.
帝国大使阁下驾到
His Excellency, the Imperial Ambassador.
我的上帝
Jesus.
国王与王后陛下驾到
Their gracious Majesties.
弥撒之后 乔普斯先生会和我们一起用餐吗
After Mass, Mr.Chapuys is sure to dine with us?
但他走了
But he's gone!
没有更好的理由他是不会留下的
It is not without good reason.
马克 要出事了
Something is happening, Mark.
只是我不知道是什么事
I just don't know what it is.
阁下
Eminency,
我知道在过去
I know that, in the past, there have been.
您和我们家族之间存有误会
misunderstandings between my family and you.
某些言辞过激
Some intemperate words.
有一些事不应提及
Certain things that should not have been said,
我们对此追悔不及
and are now regretted.
但我们同身处现实之中
But we both live in a real world.
理应通关达变 适时交友
We must take our friends as we find them.
我知道皇帝陛下非常热衷于保持
I know the Emperor is keen to protect.
他与英格兰的贸易往来关系
his lucrative trade links with England.
而显然我的家族
And obviously my family is in a position.
可以助他一臂之力
to help and assist him.
我们也正决定要这么做
which is what we are determined to do.
所以我们为何不一杯泯恩仇 重新开始
So I think we should drink a toast to new beginnings,
让我们为友谊干杯 扶持共进
and new friendships and to a mutually beneficial future.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Salut. - Salut.
干杯
Salut.
请问阁下从哪儿来呢
And where are you from, Excellency?
我为身为米兰大使而自豪 夫人
I am proud to be the Ambassador from Milan, Madam.
米兰
Ah, Milan.
你们过去被法国占领了吧？
Were you not occupied by the French?
其实 我们仍然
Alas, we are still.
被法国的军队占领着
occupied by French troops.
那你一定同意
Then you will agree with me that.
法国人事事欺诈
the French are deceitful in everything?
事实上 在场的哪位能告诉我
In fact, can anyone here tell me that.
法国人是地道的谎言家和伪君子
the French are anything but liars and hypocrites?
他们说过真话吗
Do they ever tell the truth?
他们尊重过多少条约？
How many treaties do they honor,
他们信守过多少诺言？
how many promises do they keep?
克伦威尔先生 发生了什么事？
Mr. Cromwell, what is happening?
国王陛下要接见大使
His Majesty will soon be having an audience with.
这正是我们期待的
the Ambassador. That's what we're waiting for.
阁下好
Your Excellency,
请随我来
follow me.
失陪
Excuse me.
阁下
Excellency.
我听说你的主人希望缔结盟约
I hear your master is anxious for an alliance?
- 是的 陛下 - 有何条件？
- He is, Your Majesty. - On what terms?
如克伦威尔阁下所述
On such terms as Mr. Cromwell has outlined to us.
英国与罗马帝国之间
The restoration of some relation.
重修旧好
between England and Rome,
将玛丽女士列为顺位继承人
the inclusion of the Lady Mary in the line of succession,
以及支持皇帝陛下
and support for the Emperor.
与法国争夺米兰的战争
in his war with France over Milan.
就玛丽女士的事而言
As far as the Lady Mary is concerned,
或许上帝之所以不肯赐予陛下
it may be that God has not thought to send Your Majesty.
一个男性子嗣
a male issue because he believes that.
是因为他深信英格兰将由女性来继承
England should have a female succession.
你凭何如此妄断 阁下？
What are you alleging, Excellency?
我和其他男人有何不同？
Am I not a man as other men?
有吗
Am I not?
有吗？
AM I NOT?
你并不知悉我所有的秘密
You do not know all my secrets.
我要求皇帝开出的所有条件都付诸书面
I want everything in writing. The Emperor's offer.
- 一切都付诸书面 - 那不可能 陛下
- Everything in writing. - That is not possible, Your Majesty.
你当我是三岁毛孩吗
Do you think I am a child,
先行责打再来好言安抚？
to be first whipped and then petted?
如果你主人想要和我谈协议
If your master wants to deal with me,
他必须先道歉
he must first apologize.
为以往对我的不公对待赔不是
for all his ill-treatment on me in the past.
他必须承认安妮为王后
He must accept Queen Anne.
我对你的主人 就说这么多
I have nothing more to say to your master.
王公贵族与我们不同
Princes are different from us,
他们的想法旁人很难理解
and are not to be easily understood.
先生们
Gentlemen.
- 大人 - 陛下
- Your Grace. - Majesty.
作为您的老朋友
As your oldest friend.
和最忠心的部下
as well as your most loyal subject.
我觉得无论多痛苦 我都有责任
I feel it's my duty, however painful.
向您禀明一些实情
to report some truths to you.
「真实？」 善戏谑的比拉多曾说
"Truth?", said jesting Pilate.
「什么是真实？」
"What is truth?"
关于王后的行为举止有些流言
There are rumors about the Queen's behavior.
好像
It seems.
她在自己的房内招待男人
she entertains men in her rooms,
和他们调情
flirts.
并且言行亲昵
and behaves intimately with them…
各位大人 这个王国正处于危险之中
My Lords, this kingdom is in peril and in danger.
这些危险并不是来自外国势力
But not by some foreign power.
或反抗我们的邪恶力量
or strangers with evil intent against us.
我注意到
It has come to my notice.
某些叛国行为 和其他罪行
that some acts of treason, and other offences,
来自于我们所爱和信任的人
have been committed by those we loved and trusted,
来自于宫廷之上
by members of our own court.
瑞奇先生
Mr. Rich,
作为副总检察长
as Solicitor General.
我任命你和克伦威尔先生
I am appointing you and Mr. Cromwell.
来总负责这次审理和判决
to head a commission of oyer and terminer.
来查明这些罪行是否属实
to investigate whether or not these offences be true.
日安 先生们
Good day, gentlemen.
谢尔登女士
Lady Sheldon,
我特此提醒你 今天的谈话内容
I warn you not to repeat to anyone.
决不准对任何人提及
what passes between us here today.
你和王后陛下住得很近
You live in close proximity with Her Majesty the Queen.
你有没有见过她
Have you ever seen her.
在房间内招待男性客人
entertain men in her chambers.
并且有些你认为
in what you would consider.
不当的行为？
an inappropriate way?
没有 先生
No, Sir.
你确定？
You are certain?
是的 先生
Yes, Sir.
我必须提醒你 女士
I must warn you, my Lady,
那些隐瞒事情真相
that those concealing the truth from those.
阻碍国王调查的人
commissioned by the King to discover it,
将被视为欺君之罪
are themselves guilty of treason,
并极有可能处以绞刑
and are very likely to be hanged.
陛下
Your Majesty.
珍 由于各种原因
Jane. For very good reasons.
我希望你能离开白厅一段时间
I want you to leave Whitehall for a while.
- 和你父亲一起回家去 - 我会走的
- Go back home with your father. - I will leave.
无论陛下要我做什么
Of course I will do anything.
我都会照做
Your Majesty commands me to do.
我想告诉你 在这个狡诈的世界
I want to tell you that in this slippery world,
你展现给我的一切都是那么纯真
you represent for me all that is innocent,
一切都那么美好
everything that is good,
那么纯洁无瑕
unsullied,
不被世俗污染
uncorrupted.
不会让你久等的
It will not be for long.
在那之后…
And after that…
在那之后 我们就能遵从内心的渴望
After that we can have our hearts' desires.
快走
Go.
你确定吗
Are you certain?
快说
C'mon!
的确有男人
It's true that some men.
在不恰当的时间造访
came into the Queen's chambers…
王后的房间
at undue hours.
有时王后挑逗他们 但是…
And sometimes she flirted with them but…
他们是谁？
What are their names?
自然有… 洛克福特大人
Lord Rochford… of course.
还有谁？
And?
还有亨利·诺里斯阁下…
And Sir Henry Norris…
还有？
And?
国王的贴身侍从 布里列顿…
The King's groom, Brereton…
还有？
And?
乐师马克·斯米顿…
Mark Smeaton, the musician…
还有？
And?
还有谁？
我看见王后拥抱亲吻她的弟弟
Well, I saw her hugging and kissing her brother.
她弟弟？
Her brother?
但我也没多想…
But thought nothing of it…
你觉得这是真的吗
Do you believe this to be true?
我相信这是真的 是的
I believe that is true, yes.
你相信你的丈夫
You believe that your husband.
和王后乱伦？
has committed incest with the Queen?
有人吗？
Hello?
克伦威尔阁下
Ah! Mr. Cromwell,
我何以如此荣幸 蒙您接见？
to what do I owe this great pleasure?
嘘… 冷静点 斯米顿先生
Shhh… Calm Mr. Smeaton.
你要做什么
Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
我想知道你是什么时候开始和王后通奸
I want to know when you slept with the Queen.
一共几次？
And how many times you slept with her?
我从没和王后上过床
I never slept with the Queen.
我不明白 克伦威尔阁下
I don't understand. Mr. Cromwell.
你说实话吧 我想听实话
You gonna have to tell the truth. I want the truth.
不然 上帝作证 后果很严重
Or God help me it will go badly with you.
我向全能的上帝发誓
I swear by Almighty God.
我从没和王后陛下上过床
I never slept with Her Majesty.
别伤害我
Don't do anything to hurt me.
你只不过是个小小乐师但最近却
You are only a poor musician and yet recently.
花费大笔金钱购置马匹 为仆人置装
you spent a great deal of money on horses and liveries for your servants!
你从哪弄来的钱？
Where did you get the money?
是侍奉王后的的报酬吗
Was it for services rendered?
我向全能的上帝发誓
I swear to God Almighty.
我从没和王后陛下上过床
I never slept with Her Majesty.
我们开始…
Off we go, and…
现在 加快些…
Now, quicker then…?
一 二 三 四…
One, two, three, four…
谢尔登女士 我相信你已经掌握要领了
Lady Sheldon! I believe you know what you are doing.
很好 左臂… 像这样
OK. Left arm… comme a.
前 后 后跳…
Forward, back, and after spring…
继续
Continue.
你和国王出访法国的计划推迟一周
Your visit to France with the King is postponed for a week.
为什么？
Why?
还有些别的事情…
And there's something else…
马克·斯米顿被逮捕了
Mark Smeaton is arrested.
- 所为何事？- 我们还不清楚
- What for? - We don't know yet.
我得走了
I've gotta go.
亨利爵士 你又来这儿了
Sir Henry, you are here again!
你没有勇气迎娶一位女士吗
Did you never seem to have the courage to marry the Lady?
夫人
Madam,
婚姻大事不可操之过急
marriage is not something to hurry into.
不 我知道真相
No. I know the truth.
你在等着「穿破鞋」
You look for dead men's shoes.
夫人？我真得抗议了
Madam? I really must protest.
我是说 假如国王
I mean, you suppose that if anything bad.
发生什么意外 你就可拥有我
happen to the King, then you would think to have me.
夫人 假若我曾有一丝歹念
Madam, if I ever had such a thought,
我愿砍下自己的头
then I wish my head were cut off.
这事可以安排啊
Oh, that could be arranged.
南
Nan,
夫人
Madam.
让他们明天把伊丽莎白接来
Get them to fetch Elizabeth to me tomorrow.
我想见我女儿
I want to see my daughter.
- 知道了 夫人 - 还有 南
- Yes, Madam. - And, Nan,
万一我有什么不测
if anything should happen to me,
你能答应替我照顾她吗
would you promise to care for her?
遵命 夫人
Yes, Madam.
斯米顿先生 你迟早会告诉我们真相的
Sooner or later, Mr. Smeaton, you will tell us the truth.
所以…
So…
- 这不是真的 - 什么？
- It's not true. - What?
- 这不是真的 - 什么？- 这不是真的
- It's not true. - What? - It's not true.
国王已经召集国会召开紧急会议
The King has called an emergency meeting of the Council.
我怎么没接到通知？
Why wasn't I told?
因为我也没有接到
Because I wasn't told either!
看在上帝的份上 你给我时刻盯着国王
For God's sake, make sure you keep the King always in your sight!
陛下
Majesty!
克伦威尔阁下来了
Mr. Cromwell approaches.
斯米顿已经招供了
Smeaton has confessed.
- 亨利爵士… - 是的 - 跟我来
- Sir Henry… - Sir. - Come with me!
你知不知道王后再度怀孕？
Did you know the Queen was pregnant again?
不 陛下 我怎么会知道？
No, your Majesty! How should I?
因为你可能就是孩子的父亲…
Because you may be the child's father…
很多人都已作证 你是那么爱她
since you love her so well, as many have testified.
陛下这可太荒谬了
Your Majesty is being ridiculous.
我在你眼里就是个荒谬的家伙？
So then I'm a figure of ridicule to you?
侍卫 逮捕他
Guards! Arrest him.
把他押送至伦敦塔
Take him to the Tower!
陛下… 陛下… 陛下…
Majesty… Majesty… Majesty.
为上帝所眷顾 圣洁的玛利亚
Benedicta et venerabilis es, virgo Maria.
成为我主的生母
in tua se clausit viscera, facta homo.
她将世界生的希望孕育在自己体内
Dei genitrix intercede pro nobis.
- 奉圣父… - 布里列顿阁下
- In nomine Patris et Filii… - Master,
奉国王之命 现以叛国罪逮捕你
by order of the King you are arrested for High Treason.
圣子 圣灵之名 阿门
Et Spiritus Sancti. Amen.
你要去哪 陛下？
Where are you going, my Lord?
- 我要见国王 - 太晚了 乔治
- I have to see the King. - It's too late, George.
为时已晚
Much too late.
大人 托马斯爵士…
My Lord… Sir Thomas…
我以叛国罪 及与王后
you are both arrested for High Treason, and having.
通奸罪逮捕二位
carnal knowledge of her Majesty the Queen.
什么？
What?
亨利 求你了
Henry, please.
看在你对孩子的爱
For the love you bear our child.
看在对伊丽莎白的爱… 仁慈些
For the love of Elizabeth…have mercy.
- 你跟我撒谎 你总是撒谎 - 不
- You lied to me. You have always lied to me. - No.
你嫁给我时已不是处子之身
You were not a virgin when you married me.
你表里不一
You were not what you seemed.
你父亲和你弟弟安排了这一切
Your father and your brother arranged everything.
不 我深爱着你…
No. I loved you…
我始终爱着你
I loved you and I love you still.
求你了 看在曾经的你我
Please after everything we have been to each other.
看在我们一起经历了这么多的份上 求你了
After everything we were. Please.
再给我一次机会 就一次
One more chance… One more…
亨利
Henry…
陛下
Your Majesty…
陛下 我恳求你
Your Majesty… I beseech you.
你清楚自己被捕的原因
You know why you have been arrested.
你同你姐姐通奸乱伦
It is not enough that you commit vile incest on your sister the Queen.
你们互相亲吻
her tongue in your mouth, your tongue in hers,
违背上帝的旨意…
against the commands of God Almighty…
你还密谋
But you must plot regicide.
大逆弑君之事
against the King,
尔后 安妮就能堂而皇之地和她某个情人完婚
so that Anne could marry one of her lover's.
代她的野种摄政
and rule as regent for her bastard child.
不 阁下
No, sir.
您的话令我费解
You baffle me.
我的敌人们
My enemies.
散布了可怕的谎话
have poisoned the air with their horrid lies.
不管我姐姐做了什么
Whatever my sister has done,
都与我无关
it is not with me, or mine.
我是无辜的 克伦威尔先生
I am innocent, Mr. Cromwell.
我向你发誓
I swear to you.
我以主耶稣基督的宝血起誓
I swear on the blood of Christ.
我是无辜的
I am innocent.
当然了
Course you are.
告诉我 布里列顿先生
Tell me, Mr. Brereton.
你是否曾经
did you ever have.
与王后陛下有过苟合之事
carnal knowledge of the Queen's Majesty?
是的
Yes.
是的 我招认
Yes, I did.
我绝对要谴责他们 所有那些人
I condemn them utterly. All those men,
无论他们等级和身份
whatever their rank or station…
无论他们等级和身份…
whatever their rank or station, who…
那些背叛国王与之合法妻子苟合之流
deceived the King and slipped between the sheets with his lawful wife.
我无法…
I can't…
我绝对地…
utterly.
对这种
For such.
无比卑劣的通奸行为
awful adultery,
应当只有一种处罚
there should be only one punishment.
大人们 所为何事？
My Lords, why have you come?
此为您的逮捕状
This is the warrant for your arrest.
你被指控与马克·斯米顿
You are charged with committing adultery with Mark Smeaton,
亨利·诺里斯爵士 威廉·布里列顿通奸
Sir Henry Norris and William Brereton.
斯米顿与布里列顿
Both Smeaton and Brereton.
都已认罪
have already confessed their guilt.
现奉国王之命
We are come at the King's command.
将你押送至伦敦塔
to conduct you to the Tower, there to abide.
静候陛下发落
during His Majesty's pleasure.
如果此为陛下的意愿
If it be His Majesty's pleasure,
我谨遵圣旨
then I am ready to obey.
- 谢尔登女士… - 无须劳烦更衣
- Lady Sh… - There is no time to change your clothes.
或打点行装
or pack any of your things.
伦敦塔里自会为您提供所需金钱
Money will be provided for your needs at the Tower.
大人们 在你们离开之前
My Lords, I beg you, before you go,
我恳求你们 请在国王御前
to beseech the King's Grace.
代我好言祈求
to be good to me.
夫人 请您这边走
Madame, this way, I pray you.
我祈求上帝拯救我
I pray God will help me,
这些指控都是无中生有
for there is no truth in these allegations.
这边请
This way.
我是国王明媒正娶的妻子
I am the King's true wedded wife!
我并未犯下指控的这些罪名
I am not guilty of these charges.
我从未相伴过任何人
I am as free from the company of man.
也不曾有罪
as I am from sin.
我是要去地牢吗 金斯顿先生？
Do I go into a dungeon, Mr. Kingston?
不 夫人 房间已经为您备妥
No, Madam. There are lodgings made ready for you.
真是受宠若惊
It's too good for me.
请耶稣怜悯我
Jesus have mercy on me.
谢谢你了
Thank you, thank you.
可否在我房间放置圣餐礼台
May I have the Holy Sacrament placed in my room,
以求怜悯
so I may pray for mercy?
主教大人
Your Grace.
主教大人？
Your Grace?
我刚听闻王后被捕
I have just heard of the Queen's arrest.
对此无比震惊
My mind is clean amazed.
我无法相信她能犯下如此滔天罪行
I cannot believe that she is guilty of such abominable crimes…
但同时我也并不认为
yet I cannot think.
国王会采取这么坚决的行动
the King would have proceeded so far.
倘若她是无辜的
unless she was culpable.
揭穿她的谎言
It has caused both the King and myself.
令国王与我本人痛苦不堪
A great pain to discover her deceit…
她竟然堕落如斯
the depth of her depravity.
克伦威尔阁下 事实是
The fact is, Mr. Cromwell,
我对她的爱戴并非仅仅因为
that I loved her not a little for the love.
我认定她承载着上帝和福音之爱
which I judged her to bear towards God and the Gospel.
芸芸众生中除了国王陛下与您
Next to his grace the King, and yourself,
我最拜服于她
I was most bound to her of all creatures living.
那么你要学着适应没有她的日子
Then you must learn to live without her.
但没有她 我们的改革不会陷入危机吗
But, without her, is not our reformation in danger?
她不是我们最大的支持者与拥护者吗
Was she not our great supporter and advocate?
她也最有可能成为我们最大的累赘
Who would likely have become our greatest liability.
有时候 大人 为了战胜邪恶
Sometimes, Your Grace, in order to defeat evil,
必须先学会与恶魔为伍
one must learn to consort with the devil.
陛下正在等待大人您
His Majesty is waiting for Your Grace.
去找出一个理由
to discover a reason why his marriage to Anne Boleyn.
判定他与安妮·波林的婚姻无效
should be considered null and void.
他期待您尽快裁决
He expects your verdict presently.
其他人怎么样？
What of the others?
斯米顿 布里列顿
Smeaton, Brereton,
诺里斯 乔治·波林
Norris and George Boleyn.
经判决 罪名成立
have been found guilty…
明日处决
and are to be executed tomorrow.
你知道克伦威尔告诉我什么吗
You know what Cromwell told me?
他告诉我她睡过上百个男人
He told me she had to do with over a hundred men!
上百个该死的男人 查尔斯
A hundred fucking men, Charles.
你知道吗
You know what?
你知道吗 我的女儿 玛丽
You know what? My daughter, Mary, owes God a great deal.
多亏上帝庇护才免遭那个恶妇的毒手
for escaping the hands of that poisoning whore.
她计划生下个祸根 确有此事
She planned to have a poisoned child… It's true!
正如他毒害了凯瑟琳一样
just like she poisoned Katharine.
我们有证据
We have proof.
她的胎儿
Her baby…
她的胎儿是畸形的 你知道吗 查尔斯
Her baby was deformed. Did you know that Charles?
所以那怎么可能是我的骨肉
So how it couldn't have been mine!
也许伊丽莎白也不是我的骨肉
Perhaps Elizabeth isn't even mine!
这个臭婊子
That fucking bitch.
我们昨天在威斯敏斯特大厅对王后进行了审讯
The Queen was tried yesterday at Westminster Hall.
她对所有被控罪行一律否认
She pleaded not guilty to all the charges against her.
但证据确凿
but the evidence being overwhelming,
她已被判处死刑
she was sentenced to death,
至于是斩首还是烧死
either by burning or by decapitation,
取决于国王的意愿
according to the King's pleasure.
那她的同谋呢
And her accomplices?
如何处置我们
What of us?
斯米顿 布兰顿 诺里斯 乔治·波林都被判有罪
Smeaton, Brereton, Norris and George Boleyn, all guilty as charged.
托马斯 我呢
Thomas, what about me?
我是否也要去受审
Am I to be tried too.
不 我们并未发现不利于你的证据
No. We found no evidence against you.
你将被释放
You are to be released.
是最终判决
Eventually.
我是唯一有罪的人
I am the only one who is guilty.
请听我一言
I say to you…
请听我说 相信上帝
I say to you trust in God,
不要相信这世间的浮华
and not in the vanities of this world,
倘若当初如此
for if I had done so,
我可能还像你们一样
I think I would still be alive,
依然存活
as you are now.
天啊
Oh God…
血腥时日令吾心碎
These bloody days have broken my heart:
活力青春已逝不回
My lust, my youth did them depart.
世人嗟叹惟君有识
For your wit alone, many men would bemoan.
诚然至此啼声鸣悲
And since it is so, many still cry loud.
香消玉损芳魂何归
It is a great loss that you are dead and gone.
曾几何时高攀枝头
The time you had about above your poor degree.
一朝跌落朋比追悔
The fall whereof your friends may well bemoan.
高不胜寒枯木难支
A rotten twig upon so high a tree.
君心难测命丧魂飞
has slipped your hold, and you are dead. And gone.
血腥时日令吾心碎
These bloody days have broken my heart.
欲望青春远走高飞
My lust. My youth did them depart,
野心悸动贪欲可窥
and blind desire of ambitious souls.
攀龙附凤终得报应
Who hastes to climb seeks to revert:
王座之上雷霆尽摧
And about the throne the thunder rolls.